<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.tanaybhomia.Whisp</id>
  <name>Whisp</name>
  <summary>Minimalist note taking widget</summary>
  <developer_name>Tanay Bhomia</developer_name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <url type="homepage">https://tanaybhomia.github.io/Whisp</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/tanaybhomia/Whisp/issues</url>
  
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#00cccc</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#004252</color>
  </branding>

  <custom>
    <value key="flathub::brand::primary">#00cccc</value>
  </custom>

  <description>
    <p>Whisp is a beautifully simple, gesture-driven note-taking application designed for GNOME.</p>
    <p>Features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Live Markdown formatting (bold, italics, headers, code, lists)</li>
      <li>Swipe navigation between notes</li>
      <li>Searchable note list directly from the header</li>
      <li>Instant saving and Native UI styling</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanaybhomia/Whisp/efc206caa65392a6eda0821d1952ed4d54ecf0ba/docs/assets/1-hero.png</image>
      <caption>A beautifully simple and clutter-free workspace</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanaybhomia/Whisp/efc206caa65392a6eda0821d1952ed4d54ecf0ba/docs/assets/2-pinned-dev.png</image>
      <caption>Pin important notes and format technical snippets with ease</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanaybhomia/Whisp/efc206caa65392a6eda0821d1952ed4d54ecf0ba/docs/assets/3-feature-roadmap.png</image>
      <caption>Stay organized with tiered list management</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanaybhomia/Whisp/efc206caa65392a6eda0821d1952ed4d54ecf0ba/docs/assets/4-formatting.png</image>
      <caption>Rich WYSIWYG markdown support with formatted links</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="1.3.3" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>A huge quality-of-life update bringing clickable links, new keyboard shortcuts, and important bug fixes!</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Clickable Links: You can now Ctrl+Click on any URL in your note to instantly open it in your default web browser.</li>
          <li>Power User Shortcuts: Added new global keyboard shortcuts! You can now Pin Notes (Ctrl+Shift+P), Move Notes to Front (Ctrl+Shift+M), Copy Entire Note (Ctrl+Shift+C), and quickly jump to your First/Last note (Alt+F / Alt+L).</li>
          <li>Shortcut Documentation: All new keybinds have been properly added and documented inside the built-in Keyboard Shortcuts help window.</li>
          <li>Bug Fix: Fixed a logic bug that could occasionally cause accidentally deleted notes to save themselves as ghost notes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.2" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>A massive workflow update bringing note pinning, robust list management, and modernized UI!</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Pin Notes: You can now pin important notes to the front of the carousel so they are always exactly where you need them. Pinned notes bypass the auto-archive timer and persist across app restarts.</li>
          <li>Tree-Aware List Reordering: Organize your thoughts effortlessly! You can now use Alt+Up/Down to dynamically reorder list items. It's fully tree-aware, meaning you can swap siblings and perfectly preserve the hierarchy and nested children.</li>
          <li>UI Modernization: Replaced legacy dialog boxes with sleek, modern Libadwaita Alert Dialogs and updated UI assets across the application. Thank you to the community for this PR!</li>
          <li>Bug Fix: Removed an overly aggressive check that was accidentally deleting notes if they started with the word "list".</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.1" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>A major quality-of-life update focusing on organization, cleanup, and customization!</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Auto-Archive: Added a new setting to automatically hide inactive notes after a set period (1 week, 1 month, etc.) without deleting them. Older notes remain fully searchable via Ctrl+F.</li>
          <li>Max Carousel Size: Keep your desk clean by strictly limiting the carousel to your 10, 25, or 50 most recent notes.</li>
          <li>Preferences Overhaul: Completely redesigned the Preferences window with modern Libadwaita tabs (Appearance, Behavior, Storage) to make customizing Whisp easier than ever.</li>
          <li>Bug Fix: Fixed an issue where raw backticks were improperly rendered around inline code snippets while WYSIWYG mode was active.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.0" date="2026-06-05">
      <description>
        <p>A massive update featuring powerful new search capabilities and huge UX improvements!</p>
        <ul>
          <li>In-Note Search: Press Ctrl+F to open the new search bar. It highlights all matching words and allows you to seamlessly jump between them. A huge thank you to @carlosjdelgado for building this incredible feature!</li>
          <li>What's New Dialog: Added a beautiful dedicated changelog popup to keep you informed about new features after an update.</li>
          <li>Cleaner Deletions: The Delete Note confirmation dialog now intelligently truncates long note titles so it always stays small and clean.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.1" date="2026-06-04">
      <description>
        <p>Added a new Interactive Welcome Note for first-time onboarding to help new users discover powerful shortcuts and features!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2026-06-04">
      <description>
        <p>Added a new visual Appearance selector and new Paper Themes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Replaced the basic dropdown menu with a visual Grid selector for Paper Themes, showing live miniature snippets of how your notes will look.</li>
          <li>Added a new 'Large Grid' paper background option.</li>
          <li>Added a visual Theme Switcher in the main menu to easily toggle between System, Light, and Dark modes.</li>
          <li>Added a Startup Behavior preference to choose whether the app restores your last active note or starts with a fresh empty draft.</li>
          <li>Added an interactive 'Undo' button directly to the note deletion popup toast for immediate and reliable recovery.</li>
          <li>Fixed a race condition where quickly deleting a note using a keyboard shortcut would occasionally cause the note to save itself in the background as a "ghost note".</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.9" date="2026-06-03">
      <description>
        <p>Added new Quality of Life features and fixed critical bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a visual Theme Switcher in the main menu to easily toggle between System, Light, and Dark modes.</li>
          <li>Added a Startup Behavior preference to choose whether the app restores your last active note or starts with a fresh empty draft.</li>
          <li>Fixed a race condition where quickly deleting a note using a keyboard shortcut would occasionally cause the note to save itself in the background as a "ghost note".</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.8" date="2026-06-03">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed a severe Flatpak Document Portal permission error that caused permanent deletion when using custom Note directories.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.6" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Added delete confirmation dialog. Fixed a bug where deleting empty notes could lock the UI. Restored deleted notes to their original position.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Added a native GNOME About dialog with credits and license details. Restored original icon size based on user feedback.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.4" date="2026-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>Metadata updates to satisfy Flathub quality guidelines and roadmap additions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-05-30">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of Whisp. A minimalist, gesture-driven scratchpad for GNOME.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.tanaybhomia.Whisp.desktop</launchable>
</component>
